Ren Kararou

Incident Response Analyst



Littleton, Colorado



https://lesbianunix.dev



ren@kararou.space

About me-

Ren is a passionate technologist specializing in cybersecurity with emphasis on automation, cloud architecture, and back-end development. Ren's attention to detail makes her an asset in technical endeavors, while her people oriented approach makes her a good addition to any team.

Information Security

Computer Science

Network Administration

Systems Administration

Automation Engineering

Hardware Engineering

UNIX*6 Linux*6 macOS*5 Windows*3 C*4 Rust*4 Python3*4 Go*3 LTFX*4 Office Suites*5 Routing Protocols*5 KiCAD*4 pf*5 iptables*4 ipf*4 IOS*4

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

interests

Ren continuously delves into new technological offerings in the pursuit of knowledge and fun. She has single-handedly created a secure private cloud testing environment using several technologies that she adores, such as ZFS, OS virtualization, and VXLan.

education

2017 Technical Diploma Cyber Security Engineering SecureSet Acadmey

A technical deep dive into information security

since 2016 B.En. **Grantham University**

Majoring in Electronics and Computer Engineering

2010-2015 High school Odyssey ECCO High School

Specializing in mathematics and english

awards

2017 Beta Wolf Award :: Voted Most Likely to Succeed in the field of Information Security

experience

2020-2021 Incident Response Analyst I

Created customer value by quickly triaging and resolving tickets pertaining to physical, systems, networking, and security issues while creating value for the company by heading up various documentation and DEI initiatives.

2018-2019 Network Defense Operator I

Quickly triaged security incidents across customer networks and added value by enriching reports with threat intelligence. Additionally created value by automating tasks saving thousands of work-hours, deployed multiple SIEM clusters, and managed a 200TB Hadoop datalake.

2017-2019 Cloud Architect

Kararou Cloud Compute, Ltd.

Leveraged SmartOS, Virtualization, ipf, BGP, OSPF, RSTP, Link Aggregation, Python3, ZFS, and Rust to deliver nearly a terabyte of RAM and twenty terabytes of storage to customers while maintaining and securing all networks and infrastructure.

teaching and presentations

Jul 2019 Intro to HUNT Analysis - Linux

R9B Training

Part lecture, part hands-on labs teaching the fundamentals of HUNT analysis on Linux-based systems with a focus on setting up a hunting platform and using real-world data to give students the most relevant experience.

Nov 2019 Hacking 101: Intro to Wireless Hacking SecureSet Academy

An informal presentation on Wireless Hacking, geared toward newcomers

as a way to kindle interest in the information security field.

Dec 2019 **HUNT System Administration**

SecureSet Academy

Acting as a substitute teacher, walked students through an in depth tour of the Linux command-line in order to achieve a deeper understanding of how the system operated.

projects

since 2017 Kararou Computer Research Lab :: A private cloud maintained for testing and learning

since 2022 Kararou Cloud Controller :: A cloud orchestration system built from

scratch